A Guide to the The Northern Virginia Soil and Water Conservation District Photograph Collection, 1962-1971
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
- Reston Nursery, Reston, VA: An area of native dogwood trees that have been salvage from urban construction areas. These same trees will be replanted on the urban developments after construction is completed. (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1963 October
- Seven Corners Area, Seven Corners, VA: A debris basin that is effectively storing heavy silt-laden storm water from the above construction area. Approximately 13 acres of highly erodible soil material in the above area. This type of structure is designed to prevent heavy sedimentation damages in off-sight drainage areas. (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1963 March 8
- Shirley Industrial Park, Springfield, VA: Stand pipe and perforated pipe for siltation basin. (photographer: Unknown), Undated
- Shouse Village Subdivision, Vienna, VA: This picture shows where developer installed jute erosion matting only after earlier seeding has been lost due to severe erosion. Jute is one of a number of erosion control practices that will greatly retard erosion and help insure establishment of protective vegetation on criticial areas. (Wolf Trap Creek Watershed) (Kenton Inglis pictured) [2 copies] (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1969 September 10
- Sleepy Hollow United Methodist Church, Falls Church, VA: This picture shows the construction of a new church where a conservation plan is being developed for the purpose of controlling erosion and beautification of the surrounding landscape. (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1964 February 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Corner Shopping Center, Early Summer '65. [photo and negative] (photographer: Unknown), 1965
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Corner Shopping Center, Early Summer '65. [photo and negative] (photographer: Unknown), 1965
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Corner Shopping Center, Early Summer '65. (Tysons Corner International Shopping Center sign pictured) [photo and negative] (photographer: Unknown), 1965
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Corner Shopping Center, Early Summer '65. (Tysons Corner International Shopping Center sign pictured) [photo and negative] (photographer: Unknown), 1965
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Debris basin at Tysons Corner International Shopping Center shown- Graham Munkitt Vick(?), Glenn B. Anderson. (Tysons Corner International Shopping Center sign pictured) (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1966
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: [No caption] Men gathered around siltation basin. [Negative] (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1966
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: [No caption] Debris basin at Tysons Corner International Shopping Center. (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: A functioning debris basin used as a temporary erosion and flood control structure on the Tysons Corner International Shopping Center construction site. This structure is located on an 86 acre watershed where 46 acres is subjected to accelerated erosion during construction. The structure has 2.1 surface acres; 18.5 acre feet of temporary storage and will store approximately 4.4 inches of sediment per acre of disturbed area. (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: A functioning debris basin used as a temporary erosion and flood control structure on the Tysons Corner International Shopping Center construction site. This structure is located on an 86 acre watershed where 46 acres is subjected to accelerated erosion during construction. The structure has 2.1 surface acres; 18.5 acre feet of temporary storage and will store approximately 4.4 inches of sediment per acre of disturbed area. (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Portions of a newly constructed debris basin on this 86 acre urban construction site. This basin is located on a 46 acre watershed with 33 acres of disturbed area. The structure has 3 surface acres' 42 acre feet of storage capacity; and approximately 11.2 inches of storage per acre of erodible area. (Tysons Corner International Shopping Center sign pictured) (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Northern Virginia Soil and Water Conservation District Tour of Fairfax. Sediment basin, originially 18' deep, now near the top. (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Corner Shopping Center silting basin. (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Silt Pond. (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Silt Pond. (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Silt Pond. (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Silt Pond. (Tysons Corner International Shopping Center sign pictured) (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Silt Pond. (Tysons Corner International Shopping Center sign pictured) (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Silt Pond, outfall near Quick property. (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Silt Pond, Storm Drainage. (photographer: Unknown), 1967 May 5
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: [No caption] Man inspecting site. (photographer: Unknown), Undated
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: [No caption] View of site. (photographer: Unknown), Undated
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: [No caption] View of site. (photographer: Unknown), Undated
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: [No caption] View of site. (photographer: Unknown), Undated
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Pictured at the Tysons Corner International Shopping Center where conservation measures are protecting against silting and erosion during construction, during the suburbia conservation tour sponsored by the Northern Virginia Soil and Water Conservation District Tuesday (May 2) are these assistants to members of the United States Senate, left to right: Earl Nishimura (Senator Fong, Hawaii); Charles Ganadt (Senator Byrd, Virginia); John Holum (Senator McGovern, South Dakota); Neal Bjornson (Senator Young, North Dakota); and Jim Meeker (Senator Burdick, North Dakota). (photographer: Unknown), Undated
- Tysons Corner International Shopping Center, Tysons Corner, VA: Tysons Corner Energy dissipator. (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), Undated
- W. T. Woodson High School, Fairfax, VA: A portion of a 100 acre construction site that has been stabilized and beautified by the application of sound agronomic conservation practices. The area on the left has been prepared for seeding after lying exposed for 2 years. (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1962 July 3
- W. T. Woodson High School, Fairfax, VA: The successful establishment of a permanent vegetative cover on part of the Woodson High School playground. The background shows a large exposed area that has not been seeded. The application of sound agronomic and engineering conservation measures is a must in areas like this. (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1962 August 14
- Wakefield Forest Elementary School, Fairfax, VA: Uncontrolled erosion on school ground where land was left bare over winter. This area drains into Turkey Run where an 8 acre privately-owned lake has recently become choked with silt. (Turkey Run Watershed) (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1970 March
- Westgate Industrial Park, McLean, VA: [No caption] Man photographing drain. (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Westgate Industrial Park, McLean, VA: Severe gully erosion on an Industrial Development site where thirty-foot banks have been exposed for about 12 months. Lack of conservation planning often causes serious damages to construction sites, however, the most serious damages occur to downstream resource areas. (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Westgate Industrial Park, McLean, VA: Severe gully erosion on an Industrial Development site where thirty-foot banks have been exposed for about 12 months. Lack of conservation planning often causes serious damages to construction sites, however, the most serious damages occur to downstream resource areas. (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Westgate Industrial Park, McLean, VA: Severe gully erosion on an Industrial Development site where thirty-foot banks have been exposed for about 12 months. Lack of conservation planning often causes serious damages to construction sites, however, the most serious damages occur to downstream resource areas. (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Westgate Industrial Park, McLean, VA: Severe gully erosion on an Industrial Development site where thirty-foot banks have been exposed for about 12 months. Lack of conservation planning often causes serious damages to construction sites, however, the most serious damages occur to downstream resource areas. (photographer: Gordon Smith), 1966 March 15
- Wexford Subdivision, Vienna, VA: Erosion damage in new subdivision due to improper location of sewer (storm) and lack of proper seeding. The outlet to storm sewer is located on upper elevation of steep bank. Large quantities of sediment has been transported in to nearby stream due to lack of erosion control measures. (Glenn B. Anderson and Joe Vaden pictured) (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1969 July 30
- Wexford Subdivision, Vienna, VA: Lack of effective sediment control measures on eroding subdivision. Developer merely placed a row of baled straw below erosion problem in an attempt to trap the sediment. Large quantities of sediment was carried onto adjacent property and into the nearby stream. (Wolf Trap Run Watershed) (Kenton Inglis pictured) (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1969 July 30
- Willston Elementary School, Seven Corners, VA: The use of a thin veneer of asphalt on a construction site that contains highly erodible micaschist soil material. This asphalt blanket provides temporary protection from sheet and rill erosion. Economical conservation measures like this gives temporary protection to downstream property owners during critical periods of construction. (photographer: Clarence Britt), 1964 February 5
- Willston Shopping Center, Seven Corners, VA: The application of erosion netting the face of a steep cut. This material helps control erosion and enables young seedlings to become established. (photographer: Glenn B. Anderson), 1964 February
- Unidentified, Unknown: [No caption] Dredge in operation. (photographer: Unknown), Undated
- Unidentified, Unknown: [No caption] Man speaking through bullhorn to children. (photographer: Ted Jones), Undated
- Unidentified, Unknown: [No caption] Man pointing out ditch. (photographer: Unknown), Undated